Mr. TEJAS RAOSAHEB MULEY

tejas.mulze@gmail.com



Professional Summary

I am motivated and detail – oriented java developer Intern with 5 months of experience developing software solutions. I am passionate about coding and committed to delivering high – quality work that meets the needs of my clients and end - users.

EDUCATION

Marathwada Institute of Technology, Aurangabad, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering CGPA: 7.26, 2020

Deogiri Junior College, Aurangabad

HSC, Science **70.77%**, 2016

Ravindranath Tagore Vidhya Mandir, Aurangabad

SSC **83.40%**, 2014

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Second Technologies -

➤ Core Java

- Knowledge of **OOPs Concept**.
- Knowledge of Abstraction and Encapsulation.
- Knowledge of Arrays, Collection and Generics.

Java Database Connectivity (JDBC)

- Knowledge of creating a table using java.
- Excellent knowledge of writing **SQL queries** using **java**.
- Excellent knowledge of performing **CRUD** operations using **java**.

> JSP and Servlets

Currently exploring JSP and Servlets.

❖ Front - End Technologies

- > HTML5 Practical knowledge of HTML5.
- CSS3 Practical knowledge of CSS3.

❖ Database -

> SQL

- Good understanding of **RDBMS** concepts like constraints, Normalization, Tables etc.
- Excellent knowledge of Writing SQL queries.
- Good understanding of SQL concepts like **Grouping**, **Sub queries**, **Functions** etc.
- Solid understanding of SQL Joins (Inner Joins, Left Join and Right Joins and Full Joins).
- Good Knowledge of DDL, DML and TCL.

WORK HISTORY

Java Developer Intern – November, 2022 to March, 2023

MobiNext Technologies Private Limited - OpenGov - Pune, Maharashtra

Project Name - Bank Application (Internship Project)

Duration of Project - December 2022 - January 2023

Description - Developed a Bank application which helps user to create an account, handle daily

transactions like withdraw, deposit and store daily transactions data in a file and also generates a separate file to store monthly transactions of each individual account.

My Role in the Project - As a Java Developer Trainee, I contributed to the development of the application by

writing code and debugging. I also collaborated with senior developers to ensure

timely delivery of the project.

Tools and Technologies Used- Java, MySQL, Intellij Idea IDE.

Key Achievements and Results- Successfully delivered the project on time, which can help the Bank to improve

customer service and increase customer satisfaction. The application received

positive feedback from user for its user-friendly interface and functionality.

Project Name - Connect Four Game (Internship Project)

Duration of Project - February 2023 - March 2023

Description - A "Connect Four" game is a 2 player game in which 2 players are assigned with 2 different

color discs and in order to win the game the player have to arrange same color disc in vertical,

horizontal or diagonal order.

My Role in the Project - As a Java Developer Trainee, I contributed to the development of the game by

implementing game logic, designing the user interface, and testing. I also

collaborated with senior developers to ensure timely delivery of the project.

Tools and Technologies Used- Java, JavaFX, Intellij IDEA IDE.

Key Achievements and Results- Successfully delivered the project on time, which received positive feedback from

users for its engaging gameplay and user-friendly interface. The game was well-received by the internship supervisor, who praised the quality of the code and

design.

PROJECTS

1. Design and Development of Deburring Machine for Bell [Final year project (GIZ)]

- Created a Semi- Automatic machine which is capable of Deburring the "BELL" more efficiently and also in very less time.
- My project was shortlisted from all other GIZ projects in my college and got funded from TATA Technologies as well as from GIZ.

2. Automated Scarecrow [Mini Project]

Created a "Automated Scarecrow" project for farmers which creates a loud noise whenever the birds or animals (Hot-Blooded Animals) are near the crops.

CERTIFICATION

Core Java

- Completed "Core Java" certification course on Internshala.com.

INTEREST & HOBBIES

- Arduino Programming, making small electronic circuits, using a microcontroller and sensors.
- Watching Anime, Playing Computer games.

LANGUAGES

- Marathi
- Hindi
- English

PERSONAL DETAILS

Address - - Flat no. 7 Krushiyog Apartment, Behind Gurudhwara, Osmanpura Aurangabad

Date of Birth - 7th AUGUST 1998

Nationality - Indian
Marital Status - Unmarried
Mobile No. - 7875397430

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the information mentioned above is free from error to the best of my knowledge and I bear responsibility for any deviation from them at any later stage.

(Tejas Muley)